all right
we are live you are back it is jack
murphy this is jack murphy live doing a
live
interview of with justin
dunlap justin how are you hello
i'm all right how you doing today i'm
doing pretty good justin dunlap is
if you don't know uh he was
on the street the night uh of the
shooting
in portland a few days ago and uh
he was live streaming and so we want to
just uh get a have a chance to chat with
you justin and see how things
look from your end um but before we get
into all that man i want to just find
out a little bit about your background
and like you know this just streaming
and stuff like
how long have you been doing that like
how did you get into the streaming
like why where did it all start uh
my kid wanted to go down to the protests
uh she she's young so i was like you're
not going alone i'll go with you
and we like i just held my phone up and
started streaming to my facebook page
just to facebook live
that's where i've done all those streams
and
uh it was it was funny because we got to
see the speeches we got to share them
with people who
uh due to whatever age
distance worries about being in a crowd
with
covet 19 being an issue nowadays
uh whatever their reason for not being
able to go down there
they could still see an experience and
be a part of
what was going on and witness it and
plus to show like people everywhere that
portland isn't burning it's not on fire
it's not
we got we got clean streets and
beautiful artwork and there's just a
couple of blocks
worth of a thing that are that are
happening
yeah that's where it all started i hear
you on that in washington dc there's a
lot of stuff going on too but it's not
like it's in every single area of the
city right you know it's just it's
concentrated zones and real focus on it
so like
how long ago was the first time you went
down went down to
just live stream on the protest i think
it was
i'm not even sure anymore i think it was
it was either the end
i know what it was the middle of july
because
riot ribs had already happened like that
had already been started
so it was middle like third week in july
or something
what what is that what's riot ribs oh
riot ribs
man so you just saw the the footage of
portland the whole time right
yeah i mean there was live streams
happening in the park right across from
the federal building there were all
those tents set up
that there were they were feeding free
food to everybody
all day long every day and it was a
community kitchen where
if you were down there to protest if you
were indigent or
houseless or if you were just walking
around downtown
seeing the sights and wanted a snack you
could go up and get ribs burgers
pulled pork they had corn on the cob the
people from around the city would donate
food or barbecue grills
or whatever they could to help feed what
was going on and it was all started by
this dude lorenzo and he just
was like i actually got to sit down
for almost an hour with him one night
when i was down there
uh i was down there to just film like
the artwork around and
he's like man is that a selfie stick
what is that stick because i just have
like a crappy old selfie stick is all i
have i don't have a gimbal
i don't have any of the cool stuff that
you need to put a quality shot together
he's like what is that stick i'm like oh
man i got it at the big lots for like
eight bucks you know and he's like
that's cool you know who i am i was like
no i don't
i was like i started riot ribs and as
were i sat down and listened to him
like cross-legged on the concrete like a
like a little kid listening to santa
claus
list off all the the snacks he was gonna
put in the stocking you know
i was just and i i held i just held my
phone on him and let him talk for like
an hour
and it was those little interactions
that
that i was down there for i wasn't you
know sure there was the tear gas and
the mace and all that stuff but it was
just those
odd interactions that kept me coming
back
and he started on july 4th
with just like a little weber and
he started making ribs and handed them
out to people that were protesting the
police violence
and the cops i think he said the cops
tear gassed him out of his spot like
four times
and he kept coming back and he'd just go
back to cooking ribs and
have them all ready for go when the
people came back in and he kept feeding
them all day long and it grew into this
like like around the corner and then it
got to be tense
and then it was in the park and it was
like nine pop-up tents like 10 by 10
pop-up tents
and they had a full-on kitchen going
where
they were prepping doing all the stuff
and
and just making tons of food yeah
yeah giving it away they have they have
a similar setup in dc too there's all
kinds of guys cooking and giving away
food and supplies and
just you can get deodorant and
sandwiches
and especially back yeah back in the
right after the george floyd incident
there was there was a lot more people
out so there were like local restaurant
tours would come down there's food
trucks
nice ice cream truck was blaring music
for a long time
was the ice cream chuck just giving it
away free too
just giving it away free too you know
and it's that's community coming
together as a voice
yes there's definitely a lot of that
going on and
when you talk to lorenzo i mean things
like that did you have a chance
you know as you're going down there to
like get to know
people down on the scene and like you
start seeing the same people over and
over again etc like
you start to get to know people down
there
a little bit but um i i wasn't
in tune enough with it like you you
recognize the other streamers
like there's saul luna uh deandre
marquis there's
uh cj cjtv he's he's a very recognizable
person trey stewart
there's a lot of streamers that you
start to recognize and you're like oh
eric great would have pole patrol
forever
you start to recognize those people but
for the most part everybody's in gas
masks
or at the very least face cloths so like
recognizing someone
if you don't know them already like if
they're not a friend of yours you're
like oh hey you're down here tonight too
cool bud
i'm gonna keep walking around my dumb
selfie stick here we go
um the you know so it was it was
just very few people did i
interact with on a continue or continual
or return basis
because everybody's in gas masks and
running from the feds at that point
right yeah i mean did you did you start
to see
common threads in like the face masks
and like the
the sort of i want to say uniforms you
could tell
you could tell when the shops got
restocked with certain face masks
yeah or when like uh uh
and amazon got a got their order back in
because you'd see like
brand new face masks of the same kind on
a ton of people
like which one which kind can you
describe them for us i i don't
they're most of them were the ones that
had like the
the clear visor right here and
they're just like all one piece and
they've got the the big screw-on
uh rebreather apparatus they got like
they got like a a drinking straw you can
hook your camel back into the side of it
like that one that looks like i don't
know it looks like
uh like what's czechoslovakian or
something
i think is where they were getting them
they were like oh no the check masks are
the best they're
they're super great the drinking tube
works good and you can clean it easy
you know you see you hear like little
reports like that and you're just like
oh
i'm out here in a like i got my gas mask
at a paint shop
you know it's it's just like a 3m gas
it's a guy and i have swim goggles that
i put under impact resistant like
like science lab goggles you know that
was that was
i was like i don't have any money
because i'm out of work because i'm a
lighting designer in theater and our
entire
industry is shut down think thank you
covet 19.
you can't put people in in seats
together so you can't put on shows so
like i got i'm thank god for the
the pua on on top of the um
unemployment insurance because that gave
enough to at least i had the 20 bucks to
go buy the swim goggles
you know the respirator had you know i
had that
so uh but yeah i didn't have 130 bucks
to spend on a
on a single full face the really cool
ones though
are the ones that it's just a big glass
all the way around so like when you look
down you can see down and then it's got
just the the face mask piece is
separated from the glass those are the
ones it's like oh
you got that good mask where do you
think
those people are getting that money i
mean that's a lot of money i
when i've seen like a fully kitted out
like protester
you know that that whole that whole gear
setup costs a good
good penny well yeah you're looking at
like 150 bucks for the face mask
and that's that's really all you need
down there
yeah if you got the face mask you know
and
shields were coming in by by people who
like
just had wood laying around in their
shop that their shop was shut down
because
of kobe 19 and they didn't have any uh
they didn't
have any orders coming in so they're
like oh i'm gonna make you and
it was just two chunks of wood you got a
chunk of plywood and then
well two chunks of wood on the back that
where one you slip your arm through and
grab it and the other one holds onto
your arm
so like those things would come out
by the by the dozens every night and
they'd get taken by the by the law
enforcement officials and then you'd
come back the next night and there's a
whole new batch of them freshly painted
and ready to go
and water barrels they were making them
out of water barrels
that was because you know rain barrels
around here are
it's oregon everybody's trying to be
ecologically friendly and
they have rain barrels a plenty and all
the people that sell the rain barrels
are like oh
well it's summertime and my rain barrel
sales are going to be jack i'll cut
those into thirds and you make a
shield like a round shield out of the
bottom and make three shields out of the
sides and
then you got you know you can deflect
flash bangs or
whatever they're hucking right right did
you know anybody that was making those
shields or did they just show up there
like nah
i wasn't i wasn't that deep into the
scene you know
i was just a dad with a selfie stick
being dumb and walking around
like i wear a white helmet my
my construction helmet is white and i
just have like press
and real big and tape on the sides and i
wear an orange shirt bright orange shirt
i'm like the most
visible thing you can see out there
i'm walking around like a sore thumb so
just try trying to stand out yeah
because if you stand out
as like as noticeable like i'm down here
i'm independent journalist
at best you know i'm not yeah
i'm i'm like a month and a half into the
independent journalist game
what what is my life i don't even know
so believe me i know but if you if you
stand
out like that then they're like oh
that's the guy that's always down here
in orange he's not throwing stuff at us
that would be stupid to throw stuff when
you're wearing orange
so like they don't shoot at you
it's it's just it seems smart
and plus uh the the reason i started
wearing the orange was because you heard
of the
the wall of moms or moms united for
while the moms became
moms united for black lives matter and
they
they started going down there in force
and the the wall of vets got behind them
and then
the the wall of dads started and the
moms were in yellow the vets were in
white
and the dads were in orange so i was
like well i'm a dad
i wore orange and support for the black
lives matter movement
ba-boom it was an easy and accidental
choice then i was like oh orange works
really well
i'm i'm easily visible and i'm easy to
miss
at that point right which is your goal
not to get
shot i don't want to get shot they hurt
they heard you know the pepper balls
aren't so bad but that other shit's
coming at high velocity man
yeah i got hit right in the throat right
in the throat one night luckily
my beard and my my cover-up so like the
the fierce beard protected it's nice it
protected me that night that was that
was back at the end of may
uh you know you said you said that
you're you're so you're out there
for one hand your kid wanted you to go
down there
uh and then two you know you said that
you you find some solidarity with the
with the mission right like have you
been involved with or
supported like what's been your take on
on black lives matter and stuff as it's
as it's been rolling out over the last
couple of years
i i didn't really know
enough about it until
this summer when the george floyd
killing happened
then i was like that's terrible that
that you know
this this the police killings
are are an awful thing that needs to be
stopped and this is a movement that i
can agree with that i can agree with all
lives
need to be respected in the same way
and when we can up the game
to black lives mattering
as much as everybody else oh my camera's
over here
then that's that equality that's what
we're that's what we're working for
that's that's
equality of all human beings you know
whether you're man
woman gay straight black white
wherever you come from if you're from
mars and you get here
cool bud come on in we're going to treat
you the same that's where we need to be
as a society so that we can move forward
in a healthy way you know and i didn't
know enough about it
at the time and i didn't start getting
into knowing more about it
until then and so i i i've
i just i'm trying to help get
their message known and out there in a
more clear fashion
and i i'm like i've not been involved
other than uh like if they've got a a
particular march going on that is that's
that i can go walk along with and just
hold my camera and be another
you know be another body in there to to
help
at least make it make it safer because
if there's more people then hopefully
there's less violence
you know that's that's that's my theory
on it i don't know how well it's working
out now
yeah i you know i find in washington dc
more people more violence actually
when the crowds are smaller and there's
fewer people than the cops are chiller
and everything seems to be chiller
yeah that's portland
the cops don't seem to
to care as much if it's 200 people
they'll come out with the same amount of
numbers as they do
against 700 people so you know it's like
oh we've only got 200 people tonight
let's go
and then oh it's a unlawful assembly
now it's a riot and we're going to come
out and we're going to push you
wherever we want you to go yeah and
that's how
i've been in the middle of that myself
so yeah you said that you uh began to
learn more about it this summer how did
you go about like learning more
like what were your resources or how you
know
how did you figure these things out my
daughters they're
they are woke little ladies you know
they're like hey
uh this is this is what it is this is
what it is and then you know do
you just go to the are they are they
over 18
one is one is okay i don't wanna ask you
about your kids really but like
you gotta you've got a kid over 18 who
is a woke little girl this is a whole
kid
yeah she's she's very in tune with
uh equal rights of all flavors
and uh she points me in the direction
of things that ought to be known you
know and she helps me see
okay this is jacked up about that
situation this is okay about that
situation
and then i'll take that information and
dig a little bit deeper into it and be
like oh my kid's smart
you know dang she researched this and
she actually
uh she's studying to be
a media producer for like electronic
media
so she wants to do podcasts and produce
podcasts and stuff like this
so that's she she digs into news
for the accuracy so
that's you know she's she's my trusted
source
she got a big brain i'm proud of my kids
too man that is for sure they teach me
stuff all the time i'll never forget the
moment at which
they actually became a resource for me
rather than the other way around yeah
first time i had to ask my kid how to
play a video game
he made fun of me and i was like i
taught you how to use a spoon
but yeah right exactly don't make fun of
me don't make fun of me
exactly all dad all dads say the same
stuff
um so okay so you've had like a summer
a crash course in uh black lives matter
and the protesting this summer brought
to you by your
your woke in the nicest sense of the
term
uh daughters um and you started
attending these
these protests and some of these
unlawful assemblies and eventually the
riots
unintentionally obviously for the riots
but uh and
you decided to start recording this and
so you've got a selfie stick and you're
walking around town
at night what's the plan
like how you get down there you get your
selfie stick like
i mean is it going to be where you live
do you have to like commute
it's like it's like 20. it's like 20
minutes you know it's not that it's not
that big
i'm in a i'm in a suburb kind of world
um but one of the
one of the instigators was that first
night we were down there
we had it was it was it was a big
rah-rah
it was there was a lot of yelling and
stuff and there was tons of chance
and i was like okay it's midnight we
should go
you know i'm getting kind of tired we've
been here five hours whatever
let's go and my daughter's like yeah i'm
kind of tired too and so we went back to
the car
and like as soon as we hit the freeway
it was like five minutes after we left
my wife calls and she's like where are
you i'm like
we're in the car what's up and she says
they're
tear gassing and flash banging and all
that stuff and this is five minutes
after we had left
so we were five minutes removed and i
i i couldn't tell you what caused all
that and so
i was like okay i'm gonna go down
tomorrow and hang out
and my arm had gotten sore because i was
just like holding my phone like this
you know horizontal mode gotta gotta be
landscape no portrait
uh been there and i was like i'm gonna
go down tomorrow and and
stick it out my my daughter's like i
know my feet are tired from last night i
don't want to go down two in a row i'm
gonna i'll do one on one off
but two in a row is a little much i'm
like okay cool i got nothing else to do
because you know out of work theater
theater profession
support your artists like rock and roll
comedians all those
you know get out there and and help
support those guys because
it's it's a struggling world but anyway
back to it uh
so i was like my arm's sore i'm gonna
grab this old crappy selfie stick that
we've had laying around for five years
and i used to make fun of you for using
evil for good woo
so i just went down and walked around
and
was down there for the whole time and
they were
a lot earlier that night it was like 10
o'clock they started popping smoke and
pushing people around
and like pepper balls flying
uh flashbangs baton rounds started
coming out and i was like i didn't
i hadn't really seen they were shaking
the fence or whatever
but i didn't i didn't see anything that
necessitated that kind of response
from them you know there are some
fireworks tossed on the porch it's a
concrete building is that the way i
would do it no
but who am i to tell someone how to
protest you know but
if i video this then
people will get the real idea and they
can decide for themselves and i don't
have to put my spin on it and
you can decide for yourself if you
thought that that was just a firecracker
if that was trying to burn the building
down
that's not for me to decide and all of a
sudden
i'm getting you know
smoke grenades launched head high
whizzing by me
i'm like okay this is this is different
this is kind of sketchy
and that was also around the time that
the unmarked vans
with the unidentified fed started
snatching people off the street
so i was like if if that's
if that is going to happen and i can be
a camera to see it maybe that won't
happen
not that they cared they had tons of
them on camera that just got swooped and
grabbed
but so just like putting putting camera
to truth
uh and just it's it's live stream this
is what's
happening live i'm not manipulating
this in any way shape or form this is
what you see is what you get
it it's if it's great if it's savage i
caught a drum circle one night
it was like an hour-long drum circle it
was one of the most beautiful things
i've ever been
a part of because out here uh
there's the black lives matter movement
has
uh coordinated brought in
teamed up with i don't know how to say
it but the bypoc community
the black and indigenous peoples of
color community and now out out here in
oregon and washington
we have a huge native american
population
and an indigenous population
and uh they're
they're under herd you know their voices
aren't
as as listened to as they could be and
this is this has been
this is where they generations far
beyond anybody ever got to these shores
this is their land this is their home
so for them to come and offer
offer support and and their their music
and their prayers to the situation
it was it was such a like a surreal
beautiful pretty moment
and it was like an hour an hour maybe 20
minutes of drum circle and then
right after that we went over to the
justice center and there was a lot of
powerful speeches by some educated
uh like law people all the way across
the board to
the super rah-rah-rah let's go get them
and then we
everybody went over to the fed building
which is literally
130 feet that way so it's not a far walk
and you you know when you've got
the feds that are swooping people off
the street we had
like when the drum circles started there
was
maybe 500 people there and by the time
the speeches were over there was like
seven
thousand and when that crowd when that
crowd shifted over
like it it was it was
riot ribs was serving burgers all night
long
so right yeah all right so you can see
you've been seeing things progress over
time right and
uh the guy we're gonna get to all the
details here in just a sec the
the the guy um unfortunate event
yeah i'm just to call him the shooter
because uh you know i'm just not about
really spreading the names honestly
but uh oh scooter the shooter
uh he on his facebook page claimed that
he was part of antifa an anti-fascist
like
what do you know about that do you know
do you is that like
they have like a real presence in
portland like were they down there with
lorenzo
you know is that like no impacts with
your daughter
so there's there's like this whole
misconception that antifa
is an organization
it's just it's such
there's no membership there's no
leadership there's not a person that you
can go
hey i would like to you know report to
your antifa customer service that there
was a problem with your protest last
night it's not
that there's not an it's not an entity
it's anti-fascists
antifa anti-fascist it's just people
that are against fascists
so like if you're
it's i don't think they have a club you
know i mean
i'm against fascists are you against
fascists
i mean who isn't against fascism exactly
so you're antifa
i'm antifa we're antifa we're
anti-fascists
that's how simple it is if you're like
for
for a a theory that
antifa is a collective of
organizations or a collective of people
or anything like that i just i
if you don't see it a like they're all
like one of the founding ideals of
anti-fascism
coincides with anarchy which is all
about not having
a power structure within it and just
everybody is
equal and like that's not a bad ideal
you know if we're all equal and we're
all you know all one
like that that's kind of what
everybody's working for so
like the the fact that antifa has
garnered such a a bad rap it
it's i'm i don't want to say funny but
it's funny to me the
like being an anti-fascist has been
turned into a bad word
sure sure well it's tough when the
shooter
right before he goes out and shoots jay
says i'm
antifa all the way what do you make of
that what does that mean
i i don't know what he was thinking i
don't
i don't know i don't know what he was
trying to claim
i didn't i haven't heard that so i i
don't
i don't know where i don't know where
his mind was with that statement
like cool if you're antifa all the way
that's that's good on you but it looks
like if you were
antifa all the way you wouldn't be
of proclaiming it was like if you're
antifa it's like fight club
first rule of fight club don't talk
about fight club
you know so i i like i don't
i don't know any i don't i can't say i
personally know
anybody who's like oh yeah i am antifa
you know it's like dom
i'm an anti-fascist like i don't think
fascists have a
place in in a a polite
culture in a polite society you know so
i i i don't i can't speak as to what his
motivations were before that or
uh why why why why would you say that
like like yeah i don't i don't know
it was very specific you know very
specific
i am antifa all the way and
you know that's what gets people's
attentions when the guy yells out hey
i'm antifa all the way and then he goes
oh
you shoot the game was that on the other
video or something that's not on my
video
no it was in his so in his social social
oh
yeah i've never seen the guys social
i've like i don't
i don't i don't care i don't care to
know
an individual that could perpetrate such
a
heinous act like had you ever seen him
around before
not that i not that i've registered
like uh i was in camas the night before
there was a proud boy uh patriot prayer
thing and there was a uh it was a
counter protest and i
always like to go down to wherever the
action is and try to offer
the democracy field trip into whatever's
going on and i actually look back at my
video and i have
the victim the poor family
it's horrible um i just i feel so bad
that that any of that had to go down um
you saw i saw
jay in canvas he was hanging out it was
like later on
after most of the most the rest of the
gang had left and he like came
riding up on his skateboard and there
was there was three
other three other uh patriot prayer guys
and like they're telling stories in a
little circle
and just having a good time and he's
smiling and laughing and like i just
watched that and i cried because
like 24 hours later i had a completely
different video of that guy and i
like that's that's so horrible so did
you know who jay was when you saw him at
in camus
no no i don't i didn't i've never been
i've never been involved with the
patriot prayer
i've never interacted with them on
any kind of level as to know any names
other than sorry let me i got dogs too
man big scary dogs
lots of them and i leave them unchained
when i'm gone
just fyi big scary dogs
mine i got a chihuahua a half size and a
full size
i got like but no i've never
i've never been anywhere to
i've never been in a in a circle to know
their names either
how did you know how did you know that
you had film jay the night before
i went back the next day because
somebody had said that they were both in
canvas
and i went back to see if i had any
interaction
with them and jay wasn't on my video
until like 17 or 18 or something minutes
in that night
and then he he just comes on his really
cool electric scoot board
like skateboard or i don't know if it
was like a thumb trigger skateboard or
what
he just comes cruising up and hangs out
and chats with his buddies and
i don't know five seven minutes later he
hops on it and rolls back off and i was
like that was you know
when as i was looking back on it i
didn't take any notice of him
at the time i didn't
i didn't know who he was then right
didn't right until she just went back
you went back in the footage and looked
for
other instances where you might have
seen them yeah because they're just all
posted live on my facebook
right so i can just go back through you
know if any of his friends want to see a
smiling j
it's there in my canvas video if you
want a good memory
you know that's that's rough that's a
that's such a rough thing
to oh like i'm i'm hard i'm so
heartbroken
about the fact that violence i'm not a
gun guy
i'm you know yeah do you do you own any
firearms
no it's common for people to own
firearms in oregon all right
that there are yeah oregon and
washington are not
afraid of guns at all there's like
washington has a
uh you can open carry and you can get a
concealed carry permit and i think
oregon's the same way you can open carry
as long as it's
broadly not covered by a jacket or any
of that that kind of stuff
and you can open carry all the way up to
like you know ar-15s and stuff like that
so but yeah they're it's their very
liberal gun policies in oregon and
washington
yeah and so you're not you're not a
you're not
not a violent guy you're not into it you
don't
you don't strive always i've always held
the theory that i'm too pretty to get
hit
that's my money maker oh just kidding
about that it doesn't this
this does not make me any money that's
right that's why you're on the tech crew
dude
right exactly
poor portrayal was going crazy oh the
no it's the midsize she she barks at the
other dogs for barking at the fence
so there you go she's like i'm tattling
on you i'm tattling on you in the most
annoying way possible i'm tattling on
you
yeah oh no i'm not i'm not a violent man
i've never been one two i think i've
been in two fights in my entire life and
one of them was my brother and the other
one was my best man
so you know on the same night on your
wedding no
yeah i was fighting him off to try to
marry now oh
the older brother when he was 16 and i
was 10 or you know in that we're six
years apart
but uh you know my best man like he
said something tonight about the cowboys
and i was like you want to fight he was
like let's go and it was like we
swung on each other and both missed and
we're like okay that's fighting's hard
i don't want to do that anymore all
right i've i've started the video
and uh you see there's the guys on the
scooter so
you saying you saw jay in there or what
no
no no jay was on a scooter from the
night before oh i see okay this is the
night of the shooting the night before
this
yeah there was uh there was a whole
another video in camas which is a little
suburb of vancouver washington
which is right across the street from or
right across the river from
portland the columbia river is the
border between washington and oregon got
it
all right so here's the video um start
to just start
talking us through it this is uh i don't
know if you guys out there can hear
the audio um but uh let's just start
talking us through it this is
uh this sidewalk 11 or 12 minutes here
i'd walk down from my from my car where
i parked it like
10 blocks away from here and this is
between the justice center and where i'd
parked my car
or the justice center is between here
and where i'd parked so i walked to the
justice center and
there was you know reports of the trucks
driving
through and doing the bear mace out the
back and the paintball guns and stuff
and
i got word that at third and washington
which is this intersection
uh that that's where there was some
agitation going on that that's where
some action and there's a white truck in
here right there
yeah that that truck had driven by me
about five minutes before and actually
like shot paintballs out the window just
indiscriminately
i was i was the only one on on the
street and they're just like
hucking paintballs out of paintball guns
or pepper balls or whatever they were
shooting i don't know
but why are you going to shoot out of a
moving car
and what anyway so how do you how do you
like get get word that there's like
oh action over here or whatever oh
because
like i'm live streaming so people will
type into my chats
hey there's something going on over here
or hey the feds are coming out on the
north side of the building
you might want to move to the south side
of the building you know that kind of
stuff
got it so they're just typing into my
chats that's the truck that's the one
same one i think i'm saying
yeah i think i'm saying right here it
was like calling out its license plate
or something
like watch out for that truck because i
was
and so anyway uh then
right here the the dudes that had been
yelling at him i was like
uh as the tall guy in the in the beanie
and at this point it was just like all
right
honk honk people yelling black lives
matter out the window and i'm like yeah
all right here we go this is turning
into a fun night no action down here
that burrito looks pretty good
i think i'm going to go back to the
justice center so when you say you've
got this on a selfie stick like how is
the angle
changed right like it's like kind of
straight up now
sometimes it's kind of pointing down at
the ground like how does that
the way it's in in my hand and
like so when you're holding
like say you're holding the pool cue and
you tilt it just a little bit yeah and
the tip is like six inches away but you
only moved your hand like a quarter of
an inch
right right same thing the selfie
stick's like five feet long and if i tip
my
hand just a little bit then it's a
totally different angle
got it and there's a there's a there's a
big thing where it's like don't film
faces
people get mad at you yell at you like
they'll be like hey get away from me
with that thing
you know pointed towards the street and
like the
you know we just streamers
get accosted a lot for like having your
having your camera face high right here
that's something you're careful about or
something you think about
it just gets me less flack if i have it
like there's one company out one group
of people out of seattle that's called
concrete reporting and because they're
always pointing at the concrete until
the cops show up and then they film the
cops
so like you know they're not gonna
they're trying not to incriminate
anybody that's at
the the protest on what they might be
doing
uh they're trying to record the cops
doing the messed up stuff that the cops
do
you know so that's and you know police
are responding
in in the way that they're trained and
their protocols say so it's it's
if it's aggressive they've been trained
to be aggressive and maybe retraining
isn't it is a thing that can happen
but right right that's a whole that's a
whole another
when did you figure out that you need to
you need to like avoid people's faces
with the streaming
i was like three weeks ago
four weeks ago uh we were over
by the ppa the portland police
authority union building and they had
pushed us like seven blocks into a park
and like we're you know over the course
of 30 minutes
they tear gas push tear gas push tear
gas push
all after ted wheeler said they weren't
there wasn't going to be any more tear
gas by the way
um who he's portland's police
commissioner
as well as the mayor that's an that's an
oddity
i think i don't think that's commonplace
but uh
so we had gotten in they pushed us all
the way to a park
and then the cops got on their riot van
and like i'm standing there
uh just filming the cops and as
as they're leaving they throw like eight
smoke grenades
just the white smoke not tear gas they
throw like eight smoke grenades
right at my feet like i'm in orange with
a white helmet
you you could not have asked for a
better target and they're just like
going off i'm like hey
oh that these pants were hardly even
dirty yet you know
and it's full of smoke from head to toe
i'm like in the cloud and
i got my swim goggles on and my my my
impact
glasses and my mask and i'm like okay
cool i'm ooh i'm a wizard i'm in
all the smoke you know like goofy stuff
like that i'm like
and then i'm walking around and like
there's there's almost always a guy that
has like a
a wheelie speaker you know and he's
playing the emperor's march from star
wars when the cops come out
or when they retreat he plays the
charge back back to the location here we
go and
so uh he's playing like i will survive
or something and there's a dance party
going on and i'm like oh my god look at
all this dance party
and this girl comes up and she's like
what are you doing why are you filming
people's faces i'm like it's a party i'm
showing the party
you're gonna get us all busted and like
was totally in my face and i was
like okay sorry cool i'll go high you go
low i'll go high
great sorry about that and so that was
like okay lesson learned i'll
try to keep your faces off because you
don't want to get busted for having an
umbrella
because that's a thing that's illegal at
protests now right
hey man um i say this as somebody who
enjoys
uh the 420 and some beers occasionally
is there any chance that you were like
high or intoxicated at all while you
were out on the night this night
not even a little bit with coveted times
and the loss of the job and having to
get ready for
a new job got to clean up got to be able
to pass the ua
you know so i quit that like right when
the jobs stopped
because it's it's fully legal on the
west coast so it's it's all recreational
you can go right down to the corner
store and pick it up this guy in the
crocs right here
yeah that's the guy that was yelling at
me at the end of the video you got to
turn that in
you got to turn that in that's the guy
okay
let's talk about that then um i mean we
might as well that guy
followed you up the street i guess or
what i think
randomly he was ahead of the action he
came i think i don't know
i don't know where he was he wasn't
anywhere else
like i've i've poured over this footage
trying to find
who was where when they did what
and that guy's not in front of me at any
other point
and then he just shows up beside me
at the end screaming at me about you got
to put that
you got to give that to the cops i'm
like i'm gonna bud i've got mace in my
eyes
i can't talk because of the the mace i
my hand is raised this hand my left hand
my right hand's on the selfie stick
and when they're asking does anybody
have footage my my left hand was
raised up the whole time waiting for
them to
to clear the scene and
get attention to the victim
and as soon as they saw
me they came over and i shut down the
stream
and that because that when when you
close it out on facebook live
that's what that's where you can save it
and share it
and that way i could go back and tell
them hey go to my web go to my facebook
page
it's right there and they're like okay
can you show us the part in the video
and i had to like scrub through the
video all while i've still got mace in
my face like i had a souvenir towel in
my backpack
and they gave me a bottle of water and i
dabbed some of the mace away
so that i could scrub through like i'm
like crying at my phone
still coughing and stuff and i got to
the point in the video and the cop is
over my shoulder and he's got his phone
he takes
a video of my phone playing the video
and then he calls it in and he's like
okay what's your name justin dunlap
what's your facebook justin dunlap it's
he like kind of looks at me like that's
a stupid thing to do and i'm like well
that's
that that's happened so here we are and
he's calling it into their technology
division
whatever they call it i can't remember
internet technology division or
something
and i can hear her responding on the
radio okay we've got him
okay yes we see it okay yes it's there
okay here we go they've at that point
they have
they have my my stream they've got my
evidence in their hands all before
i ever got like washed out with me
got my face washed but because 20
minutes or so
later the medics had
gotten gotten done taking care of the
victim
and they came over and like hit me with
some soap and rags and like baby wipes
and
they got special stuff that they use i
guess it came out of a bottle i'd never
seen before
and uh right they washed me out
at that moment though i mean we're
jumping ahead a little bit but you
brought it up so
kart's ahead of the horse yeah um
do you do you work around like loud
sounds or
gunshots or i'm a rock and roll lighting
designer
i stand in front of pas all day
like giant audio systems i'm deaf as a
post
you know like my wife my wife and kids
are like
hey i'm like yeah i can hear you now
we've been yelling at you for five
minutes you know
like i'm i've been doing it for 22 years
and i started touring as a lighting
designer in 98. so yeah i'm around loud
things
often every time they check a pa and
they don't have stuff hooked up right
and it goes
plop right right there in front of it
you know
have you ever been around have you ever
been in the presence of a
weapon discharged like that no
never no i mean it's
it uh all the the flash bangs and the
tear gas canisters and all that stuff
being lobbed by the
by the the feds and the cops down there
but it's it's a totally different thing
yeah it's a it's a totally different
sound it's way sharp
it's way loud yeah describe this
describe the sound of the bullets
and uh and then describe your reaction
it it so
the first thing i saw was the end and i
told the cops and i
firmly believed that it was like
a second and a half between the mace
and the gunshots i firmly believed that
at the time and i go back and watch the
video and i'm like you're wrong your
brain is wrong
your brain slowed down time for you in
that moment
to help protect you from the whatever
was going on
and like your brain does that in
traumatic situations you know
if you break your arm your
your brain will fill you with endorphins
to help you out
you know that kind of stuff and so yep
but their mace
like i saw the whole stream because when
i heard the yelling
that's the first time i registered that
there was even anything over there
you know it was like i was paying way
more attention to the cars
that were revving and stuff and
i i heard the i saw the bear mace come
out
and then i heard the the quick reports
just boom boom one right after the other
and i was like that's
that's different that's that's dangerous
that's what am i gonna do and there's
like a mailbox on that corner
that i was waiting to hide behind it's
like a big steel
you know the mailboxes that have been
being pulled out and there's all the
you know the mailbox everybody knows
what the big blue mailboxes look like
there was one of those like that's where
you i don't know right
the the whole in washington we do in
oregon we do
i don't know about everywhere else all
right so you're getting you're the the
shots ring out
and i'm i'm like police in my space i'm
like okay that's where i'm gonna hide
that's where what's going on over there
and like the phone was on it but my head
was on a swivel the whole time
you know where where am i gonna go what
am i gonna do and it was
totally by accident that the phone was
on because i think i was crossing the
street at the time
when it happened and like then
as they're running one way and and jay
turns and takes the few last steps
like that's when that's when the bear
maze hit me and i was
you know 30 feet away from it
and so by the time
by the time i saw him go face down
and the other guys were already gone up
around the corner like they
as far as i knew they went north on
third and then hooked a west on
alder or whatever that corner was i
think it's alder
and so they had booked out of the
intersection
and that's when that's when the bear
maze hit me and i was like
just trying to stumble to a safe a safe
spot
and then like what is going on
is there going to be more is there and
then like
in no time the cops were there i mean
they were like they must have been right
at the other end of that block
like they they probably passed the guy
in white as they were driving down the
street
or if he ducked into the parking garage
what happened
what did you feel in your body when the
gunshots went out did you feel anything
did you flinch
did you crouch down like what happened
no i didn't i didn't crouch down
but like i just you know i i tensed up
and froze
probably more than anything because i'm
you know a scared little
non-fighter like i was like oh no like
dear in the headlights what's going on
okay what's going to be safe where it's
going to be safe uh
okay is the danger over you know and
then
just the shock of watching the guy go
down and then the bear mace
the bear mace hit me and i i knew that i
was
not going to be of any assistance
i knew that i was not going to be of any
assistance
to the to the victim at any point
because i was incapacitated you know
stay out of the if you're hurt stay out
of the scene
let the more hurt of the individuals get
taken care of
that's not you know i'm not i i
i'm not the i'm not the one that's in
the most trouble here by any means
necessary so just
sit down and shut up and wait your turn
right yeah
right so i wasn't yeah
all right so here we go we cued it up
again oh there they are damn there they
are right there
where's where's the girl in the silver
in black dress
that's what nobody's asking
who's she which one she was with these
three people here
on the left she was with them the whole
time
like over at the other side of the
intersection if you back it up you can
see her over there
she's yeah i don't know i don't know
where i don't know
who she is i don't know who the other
guy is but the other the guy walking
with him is the other one that runs away
after the shooting happens
that would be subject number two as
identified oh
in the police report yeah i haven't seen
it yet i heard i
the uh detectives notified me that it
was going to be released and that my
statement was going to be released
it was released today okay so you're
just you're just looking down the other
way of the street and now you turn back
this way
when the shooter has come down the
street taking a right
in front of his right in front of you i
think i think he was watching my camera
view so he didn't get in it
what makes you think that because if if
you
back it up a little bit he's with them
and then he separates off because they
go down i think they go down one side of
me and he goes down the other
right so there he is right there you're
right so this is black and silver dress
and number two and
i think that i think that the white
clothes individual is
to their right it's like way out of
range
this is pretty bad luck on your part you
you see this you see the hey give the
video
the camo crocs i got but
the other guys i don't so yeah thank you
there you go
the shooter right there no this is
silver dress and victim number earth
suspect number two right there old
sandals right there
he jumped oh he just walked that was his
that was his feet
yeah dude he walked across the crosswalk
right at you but you had the camera down
unfortunately there
unfortunately so he's so he's behind
camo crocs guy
there he is right there on the white
line right there oh god right
holy crap so you just noticed that just
so he's
yeah never never realized he was right
there before because i've always been
i've always focused on camo croc guy
just be like ah that's the guy that's
the guy that was telling me to give it
away
yeah i was like i'm gonna give it away i
promise you i 100
i'm going to do that yeah so the shooter
walked
right directly at you the shooter walked
directly at you right here 16
15 right there on the right i almost got
it
now i'm down uh
bam the leverage on your pool cue of a
selfie stick
is quite a bit right it sucks you just
move your hand a little bit and all of a
sudden you can't see so now you turned
i guess that's north now you've turned
back south
that was east then now we're heading
south south there we go we're heading
south
okay so is he talking to those two right
there
no idea i didn't even register that
those three were
a thing until i went back and looked at
it you know later on
i would have thank you and talk to them
right there sure does
does he yep right there i don't know
it's it's so funny it's so small
talking talking talking so they're
together
and they were together on the other side
of the intersection too
yeah yeah i don't know who jogger guy is
you can see this
so you're uh and this is the kind of
stuff that i find and look at all the
time i'm like oh my god that's so pretty
this is what you think that you're
stoned dude you're like yeah
i can understand that bro and i have
been before and i appreciate all the
all the beautiful art and like the tag
art and everything that's just something
that i
like it's beautiful it's something that
out of all the horror of
the the the first three days of
of portland getting messed up the
when they came back in with the boards
and the window on the windows
portland chose to make locations for
people to have art
yeah and here comes the lotus and bean
on the left and i was like whoa
this is you know we are open promoting
local businesses
it's another thing i do hey come on down
and eat you know the lotus and bean
i can hear the audio from the video in
my headphones but you can't hear it so
it's funny all right so who's this
no idea have you seen them before
not i mean not not to register
i know what the vehicle looks like now
because i've watched the video a hundred
times
but i'd until a couple days ago i didn't
even register that that was the car
that had stopped up the hill yeah
no idea about it yeah it's yeah
what about this red car back there did
you ever see that before too
that that's a car that has been around
a bunch like that one and the black
chart the other black charger
they're they're around all the time
because like
who are no idea they just they block
intersections for marches to go through
and stuff like that but i don't know i
don't know who
the individuals are but they're you know
they're i don't want to call them
security for the blm movement
but they help make sure that no one
drives through crowds
when people are on marches so you've
seen you've seen
this car the red car the chargers
there's a white one too a white one
you've seen them more than one night
out on the town blocking streets so that
protesters can move around
like like specifically at the federal
building
they'll just park them in the
intersection they'll park them across
the intersection like nose nose or
bumper to bumper
and then they don't they don't like
cruise around they just park them so
that nobody can drive
through that side of the crowd you know
and they're they're chargers
so what's that here
oh yeah that's where like coming up my
wife's like hey
where where are you what are you doing
how much you know anyway
uh my my team is behind me all the way
good and then they you know they they
rev
they'll rev their engines they're super
loud they got the pipes
so you can hear them coming and
when i like right around here is when i
say oh good there's
revving engines that's great or i'm
happy to
happy about that or something like that
why why did you say that
because i'm being sarcastic because
right after that i say
not really and the
the reason i i hate them and that
they're triggers
is because i was at the ppa the night
the truck drove through dragging the
motorcycle and almost took out the wall
of moms
or the moms for black lives united and
barreled through the fence i was like
eight feet away from that
so like him that sound of revving
engines
is a trigger because of that night so
like when i
hear revving engines i go ahead on a
swivel trying to figure out if it's
somebody trying to do harm or if it's
just somebody showing off their car
or if it you know because you don't want
a male actor running you down when
you're trying to
cross an intersection just you know if
you're paying attention to your selfie
stick you know i get mowed down by some
mal actor that's been revving his engine
but if you
hear the engines like that's a trigger
for me because of that night at the ppa
right right you know about that one
right
uh not all the details honestly but but
i mean you know that it happened yeah i
definitely know that
the truck drove up on the sidewalk
around the cars that were blocking the
street
and drove through the the barricade
and then one of the one of the the
put the protector bicycle motorcycles
that do it
they like line up and they they block
intersections with the motorcycles and
just say hey we got a march coming
through just hold on for a second
he drove up and put his motorcycle
in front of the truck and then the truck
vroom vroom and
smashed over his motorcycle and almost
got him
and then drove through and the only
reason that the moms from
black lives the moms united for black
lives didn't get mowed down because it
was because of that guy
on the motorcycle giving the pause
while the guy revved his engine to try
to mow people down
so so let's just establish this one more
time
you have seen this car the red car and
the eventual charger
which i think pulls up at that stop
light there i heard you just say revving
the engines
there's the charger okay he was right he
was revving down the street and then
he's like
okay i'm gonna stop right now all right
that's a waste of gas bro do you
see any connection between that charger
and the guys this guy
i the red charger and the black charger
and this and this uh yeah i
i not not at the time nor do i now
i like i don't register having seen that
that black suv right there before
by before you mean like before this
conversation or before
before this incident before this
incident yeah never
that is not that is not a car i
recognize
i love it when i hear the rev ninjas
not really it kind of scares me you
heard me say not really it kind of
scares me
yeah yeah that's great that's right
because it kind of scares me
yeah i understand that so the charger
pulls up to the red light the white cars
pass
and now you can see right there
why do you think through the protesters
last night
yeah they definitely drove through last
the protesters
wife i heard you no they drove through
the protesters in portland last night
oh in in new york as well and new york
as well he says
oh really yeah and then after the
protest last night
there was a girl that was just riding on
her way home from work
late night and somebody hit her on her
bicycle in the car and she passed
so like that that happened last night
too like what is
the world is oh it is it is but let's
just stay on top right here so it's 18
minutes right here and like we've just
seen
the black charger pull up he is
stopped at the red light you just said
you're scared
you turn left the two white cars pass
and then there's like the first chance
that we see
um the shooter come out into the middle
of the street there's another person off
to his right of that vehicle
why do you think that that black jeep
and that red charger
pulled up rev their engines through a
green light like that
and then just stopped right dead in the
middle of the street why do you think
they both
stopped right there cars that you said
earlier that you've seen around blocking
traffic
and being sort of like in charge or
security or whatever
i'd i have no idea i don't know what
i don't know what they were doing hey
hey but you've no you've noticed this in
your
review of the video before right yeah
and i i don't know
why they were stopped i don't know
i don't know i don't know i'm not i'm
not affiliated with any of the people
at all in this situation i don't know
what i don't know what they stopped for
yeah no dude i hear you you just you're
the closest person to the scene that
i've been able to know
when we've got the video and you've got
you know the video says one thing your
vibes and
you know just like your spidey sense
that you had
up that night uh you know that adds to
the ads to it and then of course you've
had
other people talking to you too so i was
wondering if you had any
do you have any speculation as to why
those two cars stop
right there cars that you'd see around
town
doing well if you look if you look real
close it looks like
the guy in the white is talking to the
car
is like having a conversation with the
car on the right so
not the shooter there yeah yeah i don't
but he comes around the back of that car
in about two and a half seconds
and i don't know if like he was coming
across the street and those cars
i don't know i don't yeah they're still
stopped
and uh there's jay right there huh
yeah it's super small on my phone but
yeah there's jay in the cargo shop oh
yeah
there is i see his shorts yep and he
just came
through there so we're about to
hit the moment where there's like some
shouting
what did you hear immediately before the
shots fired
like it sounded like do you want to go
but
to me at the time you know like do you
want to fight you want to go that kind
of thing
but going back i've seen the other video
and that's not what they said
like i said i'm deaf as a post and i was
you know 40 feet away
50 feet away yeah that's true so very
close you know
i was not what do you think now like
after listening that
we got we got a couple of them right
here and
i don't know i can't tell who says it
like you can't match
voices it's hard to because it's just
two gravelly voices that are yelling
and it's i can't i don't i can't
i can't tell who says anything i've had
i've had that same question asked
by a bunch of people who do you think
started the yelling and i don't know
i don't know to me echo location like if
a train's coming at you it sounds
different than
it does if the train's pointed away from
you it sounded like the voices were
pointed at me
yeah so i don't yeah so in the police in
the police report
and in your earlier reports you said
that it it
there was this sense that there was a
gonna be a fight
um but like do you see anybody there in
front of jay that may be
someone to fight that looks like the guy
in the white
house yeah if that's it if i would if i
was expecting a fight the two guys that
are standing there in cargo shorts and
the white shirt that would be
okay that's gonna fight oh wow there's
but looking at this though looking at
this like
uh the shooter comes across the street
from the left
talks to the guy or it looks like he's
talking to the guy in the car
and then just walks right
up to him didn't have any interaction
with him prior to this moment at all
none there was no fight there was no
conflict there was no anything nothing
that drew my attention
yeah and so there then then there's like
two yells
yep it's like boom back and forth yell
mace boom boom
the mate the meat from the mace comes
out first
yeah yeah the mace came out first
like the mace came out of the canister
and then there was two shots
yeah just gonna play one more time there
goes the cars and the white
shooter again i can't hear it so i can't
yeah you know
right here right here boom boom
and so yeah then there's you can see
that
that's subject number two right subject
number two comes back in
in about eight seconds whatever yeah
so there's there's shooter shooter is
now
off and running and going down the
street
right let's see what happens here so who
do you see this dude with the skateboard
yeah he was on the sidewalk on the right
he was on the sidewalk on the right like
getting ready to go out and i think he's
a streamer because
he like picks up his his flashlight and
stuff and it looks like the flash on the
top of his camera
so i'd be interested to see his video
all right so
he was screaming at the time or guy may
have a stream
there goes the suv the charger the third
the second charger
shooter comes across the street there's
jay
mace shots bow bow
white truck obscures yup thanks thanks
white truck
different white truck by the way not the
same white truck right so subject number
two goes running
and then the shooter is backing away
skateboard skateboard guys walking
around
walking around and he took a bunch of
that mace and he picks up his board
right there
yeah i think is yeah and i think his
like see there's his camera
or his flash oh yeah so i think that's
his like because a lot of the streamers
have
their flash on top of their camera
looked like he was covering his face as
he walked by you didn't it
we were all in a cloud of mace he
probably was covering his face from the
mace
yeah that's possible so there's that
black charger who's that chick that gets
out of the car
i think she's the one that tries to help
us as a street medic right
okay
i'll think about that for a second that
black charger was sitting there
waiting waiting waiting
then those red car and the black car
stop in the middle of the street then
they yell out here's here we got when we
got one
he shoots the shooter shoots j j goes
down the black charger runs through the
red light
who has just been sitting there idling
and waiting and out pops this chick
yeah that lady goes over directly to him
and doesn't she
try to offer assistance
if you just saw a shooting and you were
sitting at a red light
and you had somebody that could offer
assistance to a downed victim
wouldn't you rev through the light to
get that person
to the situation to offer assistance
faster i suppose that's what
that's why they were stopped at the red
light and it was a red light there too
and you're like i'm not gonna be able to
help anybody here
because i got mace in my face that's
true they didn't get maced
but they did not they were in a car and
see how fast the cops got there
yeah like they were just up the street
so
yeah in your in your repo in a report in
the police report
you said to the cops that you thought
you saw jay reach into his pocket
reach for a gun reach for
the bear mace reach for something he
pulled up something
a cloud of bear miss erupted that's what
i assume
you know that's what i assume he pulled
he probably had one i i don't know
the the mace there because his uh papa
sets down a cannon mace in the other
video
he sets it down right beside him and
then there was a can of mace that had a
hole through it
so probably the giant cloud erupted when
the bullet went through his
can of mace if i had to guess yeah that
was that
so when he brought it up and
shot the mace they shot through his
right through his can and got him
that's that weaponry should never be
brought to a protest
never nobody should have weaponry at a
protest none
no knives no guns no paintball guns that
leave it at home
no screws through shields no firearms no
sidearms
none of that that doesn't belong in
these situations i'm completely and 100
against violence
at the protest you know it's
it's horrible what happened
unequivocably
i denounce violence of any kind i just
want that
like point blank clear i had nothing to
do with any of this the theories going
around that i was connected to these
cars in any way shape or form
i had nothing to do with it i like want
to dispel that
hard because i i didn't i'm just a
i'm just a silly guy with a selfie stick
i was in the
wrong place at the wrong time
at the right at the right time depending
on how you look at it because i'm the
only one
that had evidence that could clue us
into
what actually happened at all and i gave
it up
right quick yeah yeah yeah yeah
to the proper authorities right now yeah
you did i mean that that guy was
harassing you
uh to turn it over or whatever um
like dude i'm taking care of it i will
handle it bud
i'm waiting until the situation allows
me to
right i hear you i hear you on that um
all right let's watch a little bit more
again
there they are running away uh i want to
just just dispel something
people are trying to say that there's
number two
number two is number two yeah number two
is back
so it your take just from watching the
video
and knowing what you know and seeing
what you saw there's clearly more than
one person involved here yeah
yeah there's three if not four who do
you think the third and the fourth are
number two yeah and uh
jay's friend like that that's a foursome
oh oh oh oh oh oh you there was jay and
pappas
and white white clothes and black
clothes
right right suspect number one and
suspect number two right
so but do you think suspect number one
and suspect number two were like
they're working together on this they
like they pointed
i don't think i planned i don't i have
no way to know
what they i i don't think this was
a planned action i think it was
[ __ ] being [ __ ] you know hey
we're gonna fight we're gonna fight
we're gonna fight we're gonna okay let's
fight oh this is
out of hand now somebody's dead because
some [ __ ]
brought weaponry to a protest
the [ __ ] being the shooter absolutely
michael r whatever his last name is
yeah i don't i don't he's he's deceased
now
yeah well in contrast to what you said
and only to to make this contrast when
he went out
on vice he wanted to he said he wanted
to start a war
did he really yeah well i haven't
watched it
he wanted to start a war what do you see
[ __ ] [ __ ] that's that's
totally terrible i'm sorry can i i don't
i i don't mean to cuss on your
go bro go for and watching people get
murdered you can say [ __ ]
yeah okay that that's that's a totally
terrible act to perpetrate
why would you the the black lives matter
movement has come a long way they've
established
goals they have created a message
they've been
working towards equality they've been
working with authorities
they've been doing all the things that
they need to do to make the movement
grow and be beautiful and and achieve
the goals
and then for you to inject this
awful [ __ ] into that
what a selfish [ __ ] up thing to do you
have permanently scarred the issue
and that is un
it's untenable you cannot
it's awful it's just so
so horrible that someone had to lose
their life
so awful there should not be loss of
life
in this situation it's i feel so bad
that i'm
sitting on the back of the of the riot
van for two hours
and i streamed the whole time because i
i didn't know
how to i didn't know how to how to
process it
other than to just just get my
start getting my emotions out because
all of that if you
if you bottle that in when you witness
something horrible like that you start
it starts to eat away at you
yeah you know and and i you know i had
like
i had 77 little therapists there i think
is what i say in
in that video and there's you know the
the police were like hey
due to the severity of the situation if
you wanted to stop streaming that would
be fine
but also we're not telling you that you
have to stop streaming and i'm like
it's going to be it's going to be right
here the whole time i think i turned it
around twice
to like just show the two blocks of
caution tape
where they had cordoned off the streets
ahead of me and then
there was uh when they had
uh they had papas and he was
so emotionally distraught like like you
would be when some
terrible [ __ ] happened to your friend
that they they took him over and put him
in a in the stairwell over there
and like they they cuffed him for i
don't know
three four minutes they're like hey
buddy you're you're overreacting
towards us we're gonna help you calm
down here's some handcuffs for you
we're gonna take you over here and set
you down and they uncuffed him real
shortly thereafter
and that's where he sat for the rest of
time so he was i was there
longer than him because they uh took a
deposition from him first
and then you know the detectives it was
two hours or something before
they had processed the scene and got
around to me so it was two hours between
the event and me
right and in one of those in one of
those videos
like i i went on for longer than i
should have about
the awful injection into
the situation of firearms and
it's just i unequivocally i would never
ever carry a gun into that situation not
even for self-protection as a streamer
you know like i'm in a t-shirt and a
white helmet that's that's my i don't
have shoulder pads i don't have arm
guards like literally a t-shirt and a
hump that's what i got i got pants on
and
and hard toe boots because i don't like
getting stepped on when people when the
cops are rushing us
but like i i'm i'm not
i would never ever in a million years
carry any kind of armament or weaponry
into a situation like that it's just not
gonna happen
i don't agree with that i don't i don't
have you ever
like do you ever like gun range or
anything no
i've been shooting one time and like i'm
from oklahoma originally so
guns are a huge part of my family's
like that's that's it's food you know
that's you go out and
you you shoot you shoot or trap an
animal and you skin it you eat the meat
and you sell the hide and that's that's
food and
extra money that's your gas money your
beer money your go buy more bullets
money
i never never did that i shot a bird
with a bb gun one time and
i had a funeral for it i boxed it up and
like said a
prayer and i got the bible out and found
the proper verses
to say my sorrow and i worried about its
brothers and sisters and mom and dad
like that's the kind of guy i am if i
you know i i feel bad about smushing a
spider but they got too many legs so i'm
going to go ahead and smoosh a spider
that's that's like that's that's that's
where my love my love goes
goes down for eight legs i hear you all
right but no i'm not
i've never i've never been to a gun
range it was out on my buddy's land and
we were shooting old tvs and cinder
blocks and stuff you know
and i was back in kansas but
guns i got i got nothing against guns
that shoot guns all you want out on
out of the range out out on your land
when you're hunting when you're trapping
when you're doing all those things but
don't
don't bring that [ __ ] into a civilized
situation
do you think it's weird man like i just
cannot get over the fact
that where are we let's go back here
17 there we go 18 minutes
that that i'm pointing to it
but you guys can't see it that black suv
dude it's just stopped in the middle of
the street
yeah and then
right here bow bow
and then it stays i can't get past that
man and
and you did say earlier you had seen it
around town before
blocking traffic managing managing
you know the best routes no the
the red and the black car the ones that
i've seen do that the black
suv i don't know
i don't know that car i see so the two
chargers in particular you say yeah and
there's a white charger that's got like
green under effects like the lights that
shine out the bottom of the car
yeah it's and that one's that one's got
a way louder engine than those two
so was this the first time you got the
mace
in the eyes mace yeah
yeah i've been tear gassed and stuff
before but that's the first time with
mason that [ __ ] hits different
it gets so much so much more painful so
much more quickly
bear mace is not something that
i want in me ever again yeah so the my
face
my face burned the sting yeah the police
report said that it was discharged and
then it was shot
so the whole can probably released
yeah so that's you know way more than is
typically
extolled in any instance did you see
anybody picking anything up on the
ground
uh the no i didn't but
i know that the cops found a casing
because it was
to my left by about four feet where i
was sitting for
30 minutes and that other in that other
video when they
uh when they asked me to get up off of
the van i'm like oh they're looking for
the second casing like they had the
tents
over the first casing and they were
looking for the second one yeah the
police report says that they found
one full casing and then a partial
oh gotcha and that would make sense that
the partial casing was found if it was
the one that went through the can
i don't know actually i take that back i
don't know exactly how that works
all right so you didn't see anybody the
casing would have it wouldn't have gone
through the can
right right right right i would have
ejected ejected
i guess that's what you did you didn't
see anybody picking anything up off the
ground
no and the the second
canister winds up there's a manhole
cover just to the right over here
and that's where they that's where they
found the second canister the one with
the hole in it
right right
and no no i didn't i didn't see anybody
policing the scene or
hiding anything or anything like that
plus by this time i could barely see
anything
yeah i was just thinking like by this
time i could
like i was like whole because this is
before the police so i like had my left
hand and i was like trying to open my
eyes and close them to make more water
come out
and i was doing that whole thing and hey
please water eyes oh my god
so i didn't have my goggles on i didn't
have my impact goggles down i was just
walking along the street looking at
pretty art
talking about yeah it's oh and then the
cops
in one of the later videos they brought
in like 15 burritos and they didn't even
give me one
um but the cop comes in and he says
something about there's mace in the air
watch your eyes and i'm like eyes eyes
yes my eyes hurt do you have stuff for
eyes
do you have eye stuff things or whatever
stupid thing i said
yeah um
man and i could hardly talk because it
was in my throat
all right we have a million people you
you mind taking a couple questions uh
yeah there you go
got to be quick though because like i
would we were supposed to do like 30
minutes or an hour and a half wasn't
that
that time flew yeah well i'm good at my
job
i'll pick you up yeah keep them talking
i think a couple of questions from the
audience
um i don't know has to be an acceptable
answer
yeah exactly right exactly
right well i'm just well i can hear you
in my ears i can hear you going on about
the
going on about the mace i i have had
that in my eyes it sucks
um it's awful yeah so do you have any
like uh
let me see what the let me see what the
chat says here any questions
um here's some straight ones had you
ever met michael r
before the shooter no
had you ever seen him around not to
notice
like i don't know he might he might be
in one of the like
70 hours of footage that i have but i
wouldn't
no and uh if you think that this is
antifa and what antifa does
like is that still something that you
can get behind
again antifa is not an organization
it's not they're not a movement what i
get behind is the black live matter
movement
and the organizational message that they
try to that they put out of equality
for everybody of lifting everybody up to
the same location and
and stopping police brutalities that's
that's the message that i can get behind
antifa i don't even know i don't even
know if
antifa has a message i don't even know
if they have a message board i'm not
i'm not part of that so
you never heard of anybody from antithet
communicating or
handbooks or anything like that oh yeah
everybody's heard like all the
conspiracy
theories about antifa having the what is
it the anarchist cookbook
is that the one no there's actually been
around since like the 60s
no it's called the anti-fascist handbook
and it has the flag on it and it's like
how to organize your ant for cell
no no they put out a book that seems
counterintuitive for
for that organization no i've never i've
never heard of that book
allow me to just tell you one thing it's
very well organized
there's a handbook there's chapters
affinity groups funding
coordination of all kinds okay i didn't
you have you've never heard anything
like that no no this is all news that's
news to me
i don't know like how many i'm gonna i'm
in a union i'm in a theater union
i've been in a stagehand union like i'm
i dig i dig unions of all kinds but
no i've never never been
never been privy to that information
until this i was
i was today years old when i found that
out
yeah well there's there's quite a bit
out there um
would you ever go out again oh yeah
as soon as my wife says it's okay
yeah i mean that's that's the the
driving force in all of my decisions is
whether or not
i'm going to cause discomfort
to my loved ones and like knowing that
so many people were worried about me in
that situation
and were concerned about my well-being
in that situation that i put them
through that emotion
that that that that really
that really that really touches me in a
way that i don't want to be touched
again yeah like i don't i don't want to
put people through that emotional
journey of worrying about my well-being
and so
when it's when i feel that it's safe to
go back out again
and when my wife feels that it's safe to
go back out again i will
i'm sad because tonight's 100 nights
tonight's the centennial night
and i'm not i'm not there because it's i
there's there's fear for me
and i don't i don't want there to be
fear for me
i want to be safe i want everybody to
know that i'm safe
i hear that did you talk to anybody
before you did your press circuits and
this little speaking
you know engagements that you've done
anybody prep you
anybody no figure out no much to my
chagrin i probably look like a douche
bag the whole time
no preppers no no speechification like i
grew up as an actor so i know how to
speak
you know i know i know how to project my
voice yeah i know how i know how to
enunciate
but no i was not coached by anyone or
told what not to say or any of that
stuff i probably should have checked
into that but
no lawyers know anything no
not at all and like i just my
my driving force for it was this needs
to be seen by everyone
everyone i gave permission to ev to
almost
everyone like rt i didn't give
permission to because that's
putin's paper and i just felt i felt a
little odd by that but like people that
wanted to buy it i was like no
i don't want anybody to have control of
it i was approached by
three different organizations i was like
no you're
no you give me 100 of the money and i
have 100 of the control
cool we'll do that but i'm not letting
you have any control
and i'm not letting you have any of the
money because i'm not making money
i haven't made a dime off of this ever i
haven't ever put up my venmo
i haven't ever put up a cash app the
only time on any of my streams
that i've ever asked anybody to donate
to anything
was uh there there was a lady who was
going to the march
the the the celebration march in
in dc last week and she wanted to raise
money to help her 10-year-old daughter
go
so that she could take her daughter with
her i was like hey guys let's kick her
some coins so that she can get her kid
to the march
and that's the only time i've ever asked
for money for anything
got it on this because it's not this is
not a money-making adventure for me
this was something to to fill my time
and for me to help the the people that
are that are
afraid to go down there because of kovid
that are afraid to go down there because
they get nervous around crowds
that are that are too young to go down
there here this is like my
my seven-year-old nephew watches with my
mom
while she's you know when she's watching
him for the night so my sister and her
husband can go out
she's like oh this is what uncle
justin's doing tonight he's walking
around and
there's a bunch of shouting and stuff
and you know he'll sit there and watch
it and ask questions about what are they
mad about what are they happy about oh
why are they dancing
because they're happy you know and for
like the kids and the people who want to
stay at home
and stuff like that it's just it's a
democracy field trip
we're going to go along we're going to
see some protest pups we're going to see
some democracy dogs
we're going to check out some cool art
you know that's that's
that's what we're gonna do i i don't i
never
did i want you know maybe sure maybe
we're gonna catch some tear gas
you know that's that's part of that's
part of democracy
maybe we're gonna get some flash bangs
if that happens then
i'll try to avoid them because i don't
like getting hit with flashbangs
i know the first time i got hit with one
it scared the [ __ ] out of me i had no
idea what was coming
it was the first night that they had
been used there had just been there had
just been firecrackers and all of a
sudden dude
boom landed on my head it's a different
noise
it is it is loud as [ __ ] yeah i got one
question that came through that's good
just tell us why revving the engines
bothered you but gunshots you know
look if you were me and and somebody
somebody got shot right in front of me
i would go oh [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] double [ __ ]
what the [ __ ] that guy's got [ __ ]
shot what the [ __ ]
[ __ ] that would be me that's just me
right so yo you you have been in a fight
yeah been a bunch of fights i mean
i'm a train yeah so
like i froze i froze when the gunshots
went off
when somebody punches you in the face
you punch them back
somebody punches me in the face i'm
gonna turn around and run and be like
hey why are you punching me
it's totally different reactions
everybody reacts different ways to
different things
and the reason i reacted when the cars
rev is because i was down
at the ppa when that truck drove through
all the people and the revving engine
right before he took the bike down that
you know that sticks with you and you
hear the revving engine and then you see
a motorcycle gets smashed and it's
dragged scraping by
34 moms wearing yellow
that's a thing that sticks with you and
that right there that becomes a trigger
for you to put your head on a swivel you
know so
then the the gunshots i was like
i don't i'm that was that gunshot like i
didn't say a word
if you watch any of my streams i'm a
jabber jaw
and i shut completely up you are dude
burritos and loaded powers
yeah i cut i shut completely up that
whole time i froze
yeah it's you know whatever whatever
that makes me if that makes me
weak if that makes me
that's just that's my response to that
situation and i've got
like there's no shame in that in my mind
if i freeze under gunfire then i'm going
to freeze under gunfire and that's
something that i know now
i didn't know that before that night
most people will most people will
um one last question for anybody one
last question
black lives matter one of their main
issues black lives matter
is promote non-traditional family
sort of like bust up the family but you
man you strike me as like a family man
you got you're there with your wife you
got three kids you know you got to talk
to your wife about doing [ __ ] which is
the way most of america works like
you know do you support that message
i didn't know that that was a message of
theirs it is i don't
i don't know on their website one of the
mission
mission points is to disrupt the nuclear
family
what does that mean no what does that
mean that's a really good question
i think black man i'm gonna pull it up
for you right now black lives matter
because you know it's like what i have
discovered
uh along doing this stuff is that
people you know can get behind the
message
right it's like yeah everybody's lives
matters
you know we don't want to see people die
we don't want to see people get hurt all
lives can't matter until black lives
matter
right and and i hear you on that but
then you know you start to dig into it
and then there are a lot of other a lot
of other issues that
they have are pushing that don't have
anything to do with that
and i'm not here to like sour you on
this man
sorry about that but you know i just
thought it would be
you know it's just you've been talking
so long i just thought maybe i would get
your take on this here it is i'm a
sponge for information i love
information
oh okay well i like learning then you
might like to see what this says right
here
we disrupt the western prescribed
nuclear family structure requirement by
supporting each other
as extended families and villages that
collectively care for one another
great okay to the greed that takes a
village
i know but this part right here and i
don't want to belabor this but
we disrupt the western prescribed
nuclear family structure
disruption is that does that sound like
that sounds good that sounds like poor
phrasing on my part
or on their part yeah you know i mean
i think that that's a thing that is
probably a response to the fact that
way too many fathers are incarcerated
at an early age for teeny tiny crimes
and spend so much of their
their lives in jail it's a
disproportionate rate
that uh that african-american males are
arrested and incarcerated for extended
amount of times for very tiny things
and i think that might be a response
to just a a way to
uh uh deal with that and answer that
in a in a in a villa it takes a village
kind of way like i don't i don't think
they're trying to
break down mother father
mother mother father father children
families i think that it i
when i when i read that i think somebody
needs to go back and spell check
like is disrupt the word that you were
looking for
they're there for years bro and they've
that doesn't mean they don't need a
spell check
defended it over and over and over again
but listen i'm not i don't want to
hassle you in any way about that
um i really do appreciate all the time
that you have put into this
uh i'm glad that you didn't get shot out
there dude
me too you know i from from
one human to another i suggest you keep
your head on a big
swivel down there dude and uh you know
i i keep my face covered all the time
you may want to take a look into that
yourself as well but
i wear the face mask for the most part
it's the face
cover yeah it's you know i'm i'm out
there
it's it's me it's big dumb dad with a
stick
you know i feel i'm feeling that vibe
for you bro so i'm gonna let you go
i appreciate all that and uh just
uh you know good luck with things and uh
you know
do a little bit more digging buddy
because as a good family man
uh i think that you might see some
conflict and and and some of what you
think
it's all about and what it really is all
about and that's all awesome
that and if you ever want i got i got
conflict about bull riding too
now yeah send me some links to some of
that material i'd love it like bull
riding's awful fun to watch but
i don't think the bull gets the better
end of it or not you know it definitely
doesn't
all right justin have a good night uh
spend the night with your family and
uh i appreciate everything thank you
very much dude jack murphy well-met new
friend
yeah keep in touch all right likewise
justin thank you very
safe out there all right bye-bye
all right everybody
he's gone it's just us i can see your
comments
what do you guys think man crazy
crazy i think i got in most of the
questions
and i think uh i gave him plenty of time
plenty of time to to chat it all through
um what do you guys think about all that
he's a liar i don't know i don't know
how i feel
i gotta process i gotta process that um
he uh out of all the
weird and funny issues that were to be
seen in that video
um i think that uh the cameraman being
in on it was a little bit
a little bit out there for me um but you
know
i'm not sure i don't have any answers uh
it's just uh
fascinating to hear his perspective and
to see
you know what uh what his ideas were and
what his experience was like
and i appreciate you guys watching and
i'm sure people will be going
through this to see what he said and if
it all lined up and reading body
language and whatever else here so
uh thanks everybody for following thanks
for all the support lately you guys have
been amazing twitter is just absolutely
going bonkers right now thank you very
much welcome to all the new followers
if you're watching on stream please
follow me at jack murphy live on twitter
check out the website jack murphy
live.com youtube
jack murphy live jackman live all over
the internet oh and the podcast the
podcast is getting started once again
kicking off with michael anton about his
new book called the stakes so check that
out jack murphy live dot com forward
slash
podcast and uh i appreciate it guys
thank
you guys for all checking in and uh you
know let's uh just keep digging and
figuring these things out
and i'll see you guys soon thanks